Showa 58 (1983) June
Spirited Away By Ogres, Chapter One
Beginnings
Higurashi no Naku Koro ni
Morning.
Good morning.
Bye.
Oh, Keiichi.
Thank Rena-chan for the pickles for me.
Sure thing.
It's been one month since I moved to Hinamizawa.
I learned for the first time that air can actually smell good.
Keiichi-kun!
Morning!
Early as always.
Why don't you sleep in once in a while?
If I slept in, you'd be waiting for me.
In that case, I'd go on without you.
T-That's cold!
I always wait for you!
I'd leave you behind in an instant.
Without a second thought.
Why are you so cold? Why?
I'm kidding.
I'd wait for you.
Thanks...
This weird girl who constantly blushes and daydreams is Ryuuguu Rena.
Hey, my mom gave me a message for you.
I've only known her less than a month, but...
...I know her name isn't the only weird thing about her.
She says thanks for the pickles.
You're welcome!
There you are.
You're both late!
Morning, Mii-chan!
You're the one who's always late.
Long time no see, Kei-chan.
How many years has it been?
I was only absent for two days.
Unlike the conscientious Rena...
You were still so cute the last time I saw you.
...she does everything her own way.
He name is Sonozaki Mion.
What's that supposed to mean?!
She's an upperclassman, and she's pretty much the leader of our class.
So, how was the big city?
I only went for a funeral.
I was really busy the whole time.
So, did you get what I asked for?
I told you, I was at a funeral!
Hinamizawa is a small village, so it only has one school with one class.
All the kids are of different ages and in different grades.
It's a lonely village that has about fifteen kids in the class at most.
We have one teacher.
It must be hard, since she has to teach different things to each grade level.
I'm sometimes forced to help teach Rena and Mion.
You're a really good teacher, Keiichi-kun.
You make it really easy to understand.
I'm losing my confidence.
When I'm teaching you, I realize how little I actually know...
They say you need to understand it three times better before you can teach it to someone.
Wait! You're one grade above us!
Why am I tutoring you?!
Don't sweat the details.
Say, Keiichi-kun.
Have you made any plans for tomorrow? Have you?
You still can't find your way around Hinamizawa, right?
I guess not.
I'm still not really sure how to get anywhere besides the school and the town.
Yeah... so, you know, tomorrow...
...we were planning on taking a walk around Hinamizawa to give you a better idea of the place.
I'm going to make a boxed lunch. How about it?
You're coming, right?
If I'm free, yeah.
What's with that attitude?!
A girl's asking you out!
If I'm free, yeah.
Aren't you free? Aren't you?
I am.
Great!
I sense some preferential treatment here!
Bastard!
Rena, let's go by ourselves tomorrow.
If that's what you want.
Hey! I was the one who suggested giving him the tour!
This is the Furude Shrine.
This place probably has the best view around!
Oh.
There's going to be a festival here during the next break.
Oh?
Ta-da!
My deluxe lunch boxes!  Special version!
That's a lot of food.
Hello.
There you are.
Satoko and... Rika-chan?
These two are my classmates, Hojo Satoko and Furude Rika.
They're underclassmen, of course.
What's going on here?
Can't you tell?
We're about the enjoy Rena's homemade lunch box.
I know that!
I'm asking why you all spread a blanket and are eating in my yard!
The shrine is public property!
It's not yours!
Keiichi's right.
Let's make this everyone's yard.
Rika-chan's such a good girl!
Take a seat over there!
Let's eat together!
Oh, you leave me no choice.
I'll keep you company.
There's no room for you to sit, and there's not enough food for you, either.
What was that?!
It's okay!
I made enough for you, too.
No you didn't!
I'm eating Satoko's share!
You can't do that!
Here are the chopsticks.
Let's eat!
Me, too!
Youth is such a great thing...
Eat up.
There's enough for everyone.
The hamburger steak's mine!
Oh no you don't!
Elbows are against the rules...
Oh, we had rules?
Eating lunch with everyone is so fun! It's so fun!
Rena's cooking is delicious...
Okay, let's call it a day.
Rena, Kei-chan, see you tomorrow!
Thanks for today, Mion.
It was fun.
See you tomorrow!
Yeah!
Thanks for coming with us, Keiichi-kun.
Did you have fun?
Yeah, I did.
It was so fun that I don't want to go home yet.
Then can we stop somewhere first? Can we?
Where? Is it far?
We might have to walk a bit, but it won't take too long!
This way!
Hey!
It's been a while...
...so I wonder what's new? What's new?
It's been a while?
You wanted to come to this garbage dump?!
I-It's not garbage!
To me, it's a mountain of treasure!
A new mountain! Yippee!
Hey, wait!
Ow...
Just stay over there!
I'll be done soon!
Are all girls in the country this tough?
I'm no match for her...
Oh, you surprised me.
That's what I should be saying!
Sorry. I didn't mean to scare you.
Are you from Hinamizawa?
Well, yes...
My name is Tomitake.
I'm a freelance photographer.
I come to Hinamizawa from time to time.
Isn't it rude to take a picture without asking permission first?
Sorry. I'm usually taking pictures of wild birds.
I've never asked them before.
Keiichi-kuuun!
Sorry for making you wait! I'm almost done!
Oh, you had a friend with you.
What's she doing here?
Who knows?
Maybe she's checking out the corpse she chopped up.
It was as horrible crime.
I hear they still haven't found one of the arms.
What did you...
I'm done, Keiichi-kun!
I should go. I don't want to be a third wheel.
Sorry for scaring you, Keiichi-kun.
Did you wait? Did you?
Keiichi-kun?
How'd it go?
Did you find anything?
Yeah!
Guess what! I found the Colonel!
The Colonel?
You mean... that thing?
The thing that's always in front of that friend chicken place?
That 1/1 scale model?
Yeah! The Colonel!
It's so cute!
I want one for take-out!
That's trash, right?
If you want to take it with you, I'm sure no one will care.
The Colonel is trapped under a pile of junk.
I can't dig him out that easily.
I'll help you tomorrow.
Just think of it as thanks for the lunch today.
Thanks!
Keiichi-kun's gonna help...
I'll get to take the Colonel home!
Hey, Rena.
Did something happen here in the past?
I heard they were building a dam.
But I don't know too much about it.
They were building a dam?
So did something happen during the construction, like an accident?
I don't know.
I was living in another town until last year.
Oh, you moved here, too?
I just assumed that you were...
That's why I don't know too much about what happened before then.
Sorry.
Oh, okay.
Yeah!
Bye!
See you later!
Now, then...
I would like to act according to our rules, and debate the pros and cons of...
...inviting Maebara Keiichi to join our club! How about it?!
I have no objections!
Can the peasant keep up with me?
Satoko and I second it, too.
It's unanimous! Congratulations, Maebara Keiichi-kun! You're in!
Wait! Explain how it came to this! And what kind of club is this, anyway?
Besides, I never said I'd join!
Our club tries to counter the increasingly complicated ways of society...
...and whether through prosperity or adversity our activities are decided by how are to...
Meaning, all we do is play games in our club.
I get it now.
Let's get one thing straight... we don't play crappy games like house.
You better give it all you got.
Why don't we just have some fun?
You don't have to threaten me...
Weak!
Club Rules Article 1: Only strive for first place!
I won't allow any half-assed attitudes just because it's a game!
Club Rules Article 2: You are required to put forth all possible efforts to achieve that!
All right already!
Complicated games will put Kei-chan at a disadvantage...
...so let's just play an easy game.
How about we play Jijinuki?
Easy!
For the punishment game today, the one in first place gets to do anything to the one in last place.
How's that?
Bring it on!
Okay, let's shuffle the cards.
I'm going to take this one.
These cards are really worn.
Don't tell me you all know which card is which from the marks.
W-Wait! That's not fair!
Club Rules Article 2: You are required to put forth all possible efforts to win!
Some of the marks are really distinct, so you'll catch on real fast!
F-Fine! Don't think that this'll be a handicap for me!
Kei-chan, I'm gonna list your cards from right to left...
3, 4, 9, Jack, Queen.
By the way, the odd card is the Jack of Diamonds.
It doesn't matter how much you shuffle them. I can still tell.
I'm out!
You're all inhuman!
You're not like them, right, Rena?
S-Sorry, Keiichi-kun.
This is the 3 of Hearts, right?
I'm out!
It's too unfair to Keiichi-kun if we don't play with a new deck...
It's fine.
He's a man.
I'm sure you can fight off some adversity.
You can do it!
Come on, Kei-chan.
Don't hide it.
This one with the crease is the 2 of Diamonds, right?
What the...?
It's rare for you to make a mistake.
N-No. Kei-chan! Did you...?
I got you, Sonozaki Mion!
Are you saying you somehow camouflaged the 2 of Diamonds?
Cheeky bastard!
You managed to get a shot in.
You did it, Keiichi-kun!
It was a close game! It really was!
I knew you could do it.
I never expected you to think of something like this.
Except you're too late.
I'm pretty much set in last...
...but I was still able to take a shot at Mion.
I'm satisfied.
Then let's do the punishment game, since you're in last.
Since it's your first day, maybe I'll go easy on you.
Well, I wouldn't want to turn you into a shut-in from the very start.
W-What are you...?
S-Stop!
A mannequin of the Colonel?
Uh huh...
So that's why Rena took off so fast.
I can't believe she thinks that thing is "so cute."
She's pretty weird.
She does have weird tastes, but once she finds something cute...
...she becomes completely oblivious to everything else.
About that place...
The construction site for the dam...
Something happened there in the past, right?
Yeah.
Some government officials came to us...
...saying they were going to build a dam there, and they tried to force us out of the village.
They tried to force you out?
That's why we fought it.
Along with everyone in the village.
If we hadn't, this village would be underwater right now.
I'm surprised you won the fight.
It was the government you were going against, right?
The village leader and a bunch of other people in high places went everywhere and petitioned.
We even went to Tokyo, and we also befriended a bunch of important politicians.
While doing all that, the construction plans got scrapped.
It was a perfect victory for us.
Oh? Were there any violent crimes because of it?
Like assault or murd--
No.
See you tomorrow!
You better not erase that until you get home.
Yeah, I know!
I won't!
Yo, Rena!
Working hard, I see!
Keiichi-kun! What are you doing here?
I received emergency information about an accident, and came here to help.
Where is the injured, ma'am?
What accident?
I heard the Colonel mannequin is buried alive here!
Oh, that!
You surprised me.
So, where is the Colonel?
Sorry! He's over here!
Here, can you see him through this crack?
Whoa, he's buried pretty deep.
We might need an axe or a saw to dig him out.
Just wait a minute, okay?
Hey!
It was a horrible crime.
I hear they still haven't found one of the arms.
Foreman of the Hinamizawa Dam
Lynched!
There was one...
"Tragedy at the Hinamizawa Dam."
Foreman of the Hinamizawa Dam
CHOPPED UP
"Tortured and Hacked to Pieces."
Lynched!
"The murderers hacked the victim with hatchets and pickaxes in cold blood..."
"...and then took an axe to the body and cut off the head and appendages into six parts."
Relatively Uninteresting Case of Dismemberment
"One of the murderers is still at large..."
I don't know.
No.
There was a murder...
That day, in retrospect, those noisy evening cicadas...
...were warning me of the events to come.
Of all the things about to happen...
Preview
What I believe in: that which I can see.
What I believe in: living and breathing.
The bonfire blazes by the riverside
What I believe in: myself.
Countless innards and stuffing float on the surface of the river
Raindrops fall in front of the house
The Cotton Drifting of the following year... is...
After the rain, Rena and Keiichi follow the path
Tonight...!
Higurashi no Naku Koro ni.
Spirited Away By Ogres, Chapter Two.
Secrets.
Can you believe in it?.
Spirited Away By Ogres, Chapter Two
Secrets